Guide to the Eric McKitrick papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Correspondence, 1937-2001
  - Subseries V.3: Personal and Family Correspondence, 1937-1946
    - Juvenilia, circa 1934-1944 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      (Includes correspondence with Forbes Leigh Satre at Fort Lewis and Camp Abbot)
    - Old Letters
      - Edyth Stevenson, 1937-1946 (Box 23, Folder 12)
        (later McKitrick's wife)
      - Letters from McKitrick's Parents, 1941-1945, (3 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1 to 3)
- Series VI: Student Material and Juvenilia, 1934-1953
  This series contains juvenilia, drawings, and material related to McKitrick's college education at Hillsdale College and Columbia University.
  - Subseries VI.1: Juvenilia, 1934-1944
    This subseries includes correspondence, dramatic works, drawings, a high school transcript, a short story, and a few items of printed ephemera.
    - Juvenilia, circa 1934-1944 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - The Varlet, Undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
      (Unsigned)
    - Drawings, 1938, Undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Subseries VI.2: Student Material, 1940-1953
    contains McKitrick's college terms papers and course material. There are two folders of college term papers; the first is from a history class at Hillsdale College (1940-1941) and the second contains several terms papers from McKitrick's work at Columbia University. McKitrick also kept several files of material related to specific courses that he took at Columbia University. These files include syllabi and lecture notes, and include material on classes taught by Jacques Barzun, Robert Merton, and Lionel Trilling.
    - American Literature (Lionel Trilling), 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - American Literature Since 1870 (Lionel Trilling), 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Constitutional History of the United States (History 169-170) (H.S. Commager), 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Establishment of the American Nation (History 175) (R.B. Morris), 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - European Thought and Culture in the 19th Century (History 140) (J. Barzun), 1950-1951 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Political and Social History of the United States (History 177-178) (David Donald), 1951-1952 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Analysis of the Social Structure (Sociology 215) (Robert Merton), 1953 Winter (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - College History Term Papers, Hillsdale (Dr. W.H. Roberts), 1940-1941 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - College Term Papers, 1948, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 7 to 8)